Q115: In the lock-free algorithm, if an add() method call fails because pred does not point to curr, but pred is not marked, do we need to traverse the list again from head in order to attempt to complete the call?

R: Não, porque qualquer novo nó que for impactar na adição do elemento, será adicionado entre o novo elemento e seu predecessor, fazendo com que a busca possa ser reiniciada somente a partir de pred.


Q118: Explain why the following cannot happen in the LockFreeList algorithm. A node with item x is logically but not yet physically removed by some thread, then the same item x is added into the list by another thread, and finally a contains() call by a third thread traverses the list, finding the logically removed node, and returning false, even though the linearization order of the remove() and add() implies that x is in the set.


R: Isto não seria possível de acontecer, pois a segunda thread, ao fazer a busca para encontrar a posição de adição do elemento X, removeria fisicamente os nós logicamente marcados como removidos, inclusive o X. Podendo, assim prosseguir com a inserção e a terceira thread encontraria o elemento adicionado. 